{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"James Taylor","incorrectAnswers":["Elton John","Billy Joel","Paul Simon"],"question":"Who was the singer/songwriter who had his first top 40 hit with \"Fire and Rain\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Jack","incorrectAnswers":["A Billy","A Macho","A Rooster"],"question":"What is a male wallaby known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Gaggles","incorrectAnswers":["Yarns","Flocks","Huddles"],"question":"Cows Come In Herds, What Do Geese Come In?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sedimentary","incorrectAnswers":["Metamorphic","Igneous","Volcanic"],"question":"What is the name of the one of the three main types of rocks that gets its name from the Latin word meaning 'to settle'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Valhalla","incorrectAnswers":["Regnarok","Styx","Helas"],"question":"What's heaven to fallen Norse warriors","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Old Time Rock & Roll","incorrectAnswers":["Rock Around the Clock","Johnny B Goode","Don't Stop Believing"],"question":"In The Film Risky Business Tom Cruise Danced Around His Living Room In His Underpants To What Song","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Seven","incorrectAnswers":["White","Five","Six"],"question":"What does the word 'sieben' mean in German?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"South Vietnam","incorrectAnswers":["North Korea","China","Laos"],"question":"Nguyen Van Thieu served as the president of which Asian country from 1967 to 1975?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"From The Menu ","incorrectAnswers":["Chef's Specials","House Favourites","Set Menu"],"question":"What Does The Term 'A La Carte' Mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"House of Pain","incorrectAnswers":["Haddaway","Digable Planets","Brownsville Station"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1992 with Jump Around?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Netherlands ","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","France","Scotland"],"question":"From which country does Edam cheese originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Argentina","incorrectAnswers":["South Africa","Italy","Mexico"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1978 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The atmosphere","incorrectAnswers":["Books and manuscripts","Yeast","Christianity"],"question":"What is Aerology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nicolaus Copernicus","incorrectAnswers":["Zoroaster","Aristotle","Ernest Rutherford"],"question":"Which of these people was a Renaissance mathematician and astronomer who believed Sun was the centre of the Universe - rather than Earth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexander Pushkin","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","Leo Tolstoy","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Eugene Onegin'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Fish","incorrectAnswers":["Birds","Dinosaurs","Humans"],"question":"The Devonian Period is also known as the Age of what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Protons","incorrectAnswers":["Electrons","Neutrons","Quarks"],"question":"What subatomic particle is used to arrange elements on the periodic table?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George Orwell","incorrectAnswers":["Joseph Conrad","Virginia Woolf","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Nineteen Eighty-Four'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["North America","Africa","Antarctica"],"question":"Which is the Earth's largest continent?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Role Playing Game","incorrectAnswers":["Real Professional Game","Remote Party Game","Random Progress Game"],"question":"In gaming, what is the meaning of the abbreviation RPG?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"underground water","incorrectAnswers":["the cosmos or our place in it","Tibet","the effect of evolution on ethology"],"question":"What is Hydrogeology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A quartermaster","incorrectAnswers":["A sergeant","A major","A captain"],"question":"What kind of officer is charged with providing clothing, fuel, and transportation for troops?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A flock","incorrectAnswers":["A labour","A murmuration","A rag"],"question":"What is the word for a group of pigeons?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1953","incorrectAnswers":["1903","1853","1803"],"question":"In which year did the Cuban Revolution begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Saving Private Ryan","incorrectAnswers":["The Deer Hunter","The Big Lebowski","Platoon"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'In World War II a group of soldiers go behind enemy lines to rescue a paratrooper.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Electronic Arts","incorrectAnswers":["Playstation","Nintendo","Activision"],"question":"Which brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Challenge everything'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["Pierce Brosnan","Sean Connery","Daniel Craig"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Octopussy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1980","incorrectAnswers":["1965","1970","1975"],"question":"In which year was Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Piglet","incorrectAnswers":["Roo","Finnie","Paddington"],"question":"Who was Winnie the Pooh's neighbour?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1942","incorrectAnswers":["1987","1816","1866"],"question":"In which year did the Manhattan Project begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Houston","incorrectAnswers":["Chicago","Philadelphia","Miami"],"question":"What American city, with a population of 2 million people, is nicknamed \"Space City\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Soda water","incorrectAnswers":["Cola","Lemonade","Sprite"],"question":"What type of carbonated drink is typically added to a gin fizz?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Franz Kafka","incorrectAnswers":["Émile Zola","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Leo Tolstoy"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Amerika'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Divinyls","incorrectAnswers":["Vicki Sue Robinson","Frankie Goes to Hollywood","Stacey Q"],"question":"'I Touch Myself' was a one hit wonder in 1990 by which artist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tahiti","incorrectAnswers":["The Philippines","South Africa","Palau"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.pf' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Red Herring","incorrectAnswers":["Blue Lobster","Green Shrimp","Yellow Squid"],"question":"What is the familiar expression for something that draws attention away from the main issue?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Scorpions","incorrectAnswers":["Rammstein","Sodom","U.D.O."],"question":"Which German rock band released the studio album 'Lovedrive'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Asparagus ","incorrectAnswers":["Broccoli","Onions","Carrot"],"question":"Which of these is a perennial vegetable?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Filly","incorrectAnswers":["Pony","Stallion","Mare"],"question":"What term is used for a female horse that is aged four years or under?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Artful Dodger","incorrectAnswers":["Eminem","Justin Timberlake","Usher"],"question":"Whose first hit was \"Re-Rewind (The Crowd Say Bo Selecta)\" in 1999?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Bronx","incorrectAnswers":["Brooklyn","Queens","Manhattan"],"question":"Which New York City borough is the only one that is not separated from Upstate New York by water?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Poseidon","incorrectAnswers":["Athena","Hades","Demeter"],"question":"Who is the greek equivalent of the roman god Neptune?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Tales of Beedle the Bard'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dadaism","incorrectAnswers":["Post Impressionism","Fauvism","Nihilism"],"question":"Which art movement aimed to create antiart and non art, employing a sense of the absurd?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jaws","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","Titanic","Star Wars"],"question":"\"You're gonna need a bigger boat\" is a line from which 70's film?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A suburban father has a mid-life crisis after becoming infatuated with his daughter's friend.","incorrectAnswers":["A mother personally challenges the local authorities to solve her daughter's murder.","A surgeon rescues a disfigured man who is mistreated while scraping a living as a side-show freak.","A woman works with a hardened boxing trainer to become a professional."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie American Beauty?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Niger–Congo","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Kra–Dai","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Nigerian Fulfulde' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hanoi","incorrectAnswers":["Ho Chi Minh City","Da Nang","Hue"],"question":"What is the capital city of Vietnam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ironclad","incorrectAnswers":["Steeler","Metallica","Plated dragon"],"question":"What term refers to a metal-plated wooden warship?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Spinoza","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Denis Diderot","Albert Camus"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'I can control my passions and emotions if I can understand their nature'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Houston Astros","incorrectAnswers":["Houston Predators","Houston City","Houston Football"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Houston?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Ecuador","Malta"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Havana?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Inventor of the telephone.","incorrectAnswers":["Engineer who helped develop radio transmission.","A key figure of Jewish/Christian history.","38th President of the US."],"question":"Which of the following describes Alexander Graham Bell?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dodecagon","incorrectAnswers":["Octagon","Hexagon","Triangle"],"question":"What is the name of a shape with twelve sides?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Daniel Craig","incorrectAnswers":["George Lazenby","Roger Moore","Sean Connery"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Casino Royale?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Lobster","incorrectAnswers":["Crab","Shrimp","Clam"],"question":"Which type of seafood has varieties called Maine and spiny, and turns a vivid red only after it's been cooked?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Miguel de Cervantes","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Don Quixote'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Isaac Newton","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","Charles Darwin","Galileo Galilei"],"question":"Who developed the theory of universal gravitation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Wai","incorrectAnswers":["Fist bump","Handshake","Khǎawng dtàm"],"question":"Which of these gestures  is a commonly used when greeting in Thailand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Montenegro","incorrectAnswers":["Yemen","Mexico","Monaco"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.me' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Inauguration","incorrectAnswers":["Coronation","Installation","Ordination"],"question":"Which word refers to the ceremony in which a new President of the United States is formally introduced?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Austroasiatic","Niger–Congo","Sino-Tibetan"],"question":"The language 'Urdu' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1957","incorrectAnswers":["1941","1949","1969"],"question":"In which year did Ghana gain independence?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Marco Polo","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Columbus","Ferdinand Magellan","Francis Drake"],"question":"What explorer landed in China and reached Kublai Khan's court in 1275?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Biologist who created the oral contraceptive pill.","incorrectAnswers":["Chemist and biologist who had a leading impact on the chemical revolution.","A religious prophet.","An influential figure in Sunni Islam."],"question":"Which of the following describes Gregory Pincus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Calf","incorrectAnswers":["A Gosling","A Farrow","A Caterpillar"],"question":"What would you call a baby whale?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cub","incorrectAnswers":["A Baby","A Kit","A Caterpillar"],"question":"What is a baby walrus known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"800","incorrectAnswers":["1100","1400","1700"],"question":"What year did the coronation of Charlemagne as Emperor of the Holy Roman Empire take place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fife","incorrectAnswers":["Maraca","Violin","Fiddle"],"question":"Which of these is a woodwind instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mongolia","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Gangsta's Paradise\" by Coolio feat. L.V.","incorrectAnswers":["\"Rapper's Delight\" by Sugarhill Gang","\"I Write Sins Not Tragedies\" by Panic! at the Disco","\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"As I walk through the valley of the shadow of death / I take a look at my life and realize there's not much left...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tom Hanks","incorrectAnswers":["Leonardo DiCaprio","Tom Cruise","Sean Connery"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Forrest Gump and Saving Private Ryan?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Adolf Hitler","incorrectAnswers":["Hermann Müller","Konrad Adenauer","Angela Merkel"],"question":"Who became chancellor of Germany in 1933?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Good, the Bad and the Ugly","incorrectAnswers":["It's a Wonderful Life","The Silence of the Lambs","The Deer Hunter"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Two men join in an uneasy alliance against a third to find gold buried in a remote cemetery.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Byrds","incorrectAnswers":["The Hollies","The Cranberries","Buffalo Springfield"],"question":"David Crosby, of Crosby, Stills and Nash, was previously with which other popular 60's group?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yellow","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Orange","Gold"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Bosnia and Herzegovina?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Kitten","incorrectAnswers":["A Chick","A Kid","A Farrow"],"question":"A young beaver is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Cassius Marcellus Coolidge","incorrectAnswers":["James Abbott McNeill Whistler","‎‎Edvard Munch","René Magritte"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Dogs Playing Poker\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Terms of Endearment","incorrectAnswers":["Pirates of the Caribbean","Grease","The Night of the Hunter"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Aurora Greenway'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Iliad","incorrectAnswers":["Troy","Metamorphosis","The Republic"],"question":"What is the name of the account of the Trojan War written by the Ancient Greek poet Homer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Legume","incorrectAnswers":["Maize","Seed","Fruit"],"question":"What is a peanut if it is not a pea or a nut?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Beatrix Potter","Søren Kierkegaard","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Snow Queen'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Need makes even the timid brave","incorrectAnswers":["I came, I saw, I conquered","Necessity breeds strength","Out of chaos, comes order"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Latin phrase 'Necessitas etiam timidos fortes facit'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Koreanic","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Sino-Tibetan","Turkic"],"question":"The language 'Korean' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mercury","incorrectAnswers":["Venus","Earth","Mars"],"question":"Which is the smallest planet in the Solar System?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Wall Street","incorrectAnswers":["Pirates of the Caribbean","Gangs of New York","The Lord of the Rings"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Gordon Gekko'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"As You Like It","incorrectAnswers":["Twelfth Night","Much Ado About Nothing","A Midsummer Night's Dream"],"question":"From which Shakespearean comedy do the lines 'And thereby hangs a tale' and 'All the world's a stage' come?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Garlic","incorrectAnswers":["Lemon","Egg","Chickpea"],"question":"What is the main ingredient of aioli sauce?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Percussion","incorrectAnswers":["String","Wind","Keyboard"],"question":"What type of instrument is a triangle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Narendra Modi","incorrectAnswers":["Rahul Gandhi","Manmohan Singh","Atal Bihari Vajpayee"],"question":"Who became the Prime Minister of India in 2014?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["United States","Italy","Mexico"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1950 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Aurora","incorrectAnswers":["Dawn","Twilight","Eclipse"],"question":"What is the name of the natural phenomenon that occurs when particles from the solar wind interact with gases in the atmosphere?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["Roger Moore","George Lazenby","Pierce Brosnan"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Diamonds Are Forever?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A yuppie","incorrectAnswers":["A hipster","A bohemian","A beatnik"],"question":"What term, coined in the 1980s, refers to a youthful metropolitan white-collar worker?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Newton","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel Defoe","Percy Bysshe Shelley","Walter Scott"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A herd","incorrectAnswers":["A yoke","A murder","A clowder"],"question":"What is the word for a group of seals?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Apollo 11","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo 1","Apollo 3","Apollo 9"],"question":"Which Apollo space mission put the first people on the moon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Whales, dolphins and porpoises","incorrectAnswers":["Grasses","Bones","Museum management"],"question":"What is cetology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Live and Let Die","incorrectAnswers":["Tomorrow Never Dies","Skyfall","The Living Daylights"],"question":"Which James Bond theme song was performed by Wings?","difficulty":"medium"},